tell us about the process and how um it
was communicated to you that you would
be like calling the players.
>> Yeah. Um so Dave, a couple weeks after
the season, you know, we always do our
recap. We we go through with all the
coaches and um sit down and evaluate our
processes, evaluate um the roles that
everybody has and and what's best for us
going forward. And and he felt like this
is the right time to do it. And um uh
just uh very fortunate to have a guy
that believes in me and and uh you know
for us like the benefit is it's not a a
big it seems like a big change but it
really isn't because I've been along you
know side of him the whole the whole
step of way of his growth and and being
an offensive coordinator from Tampa to
here. Um and that that part's been fun.
Um pinging ideas off each other,
learning from his experiences. Uh so
when he brought that up to me I'm I'm
honored. I'm flattered and it's
obviously from a personal standpoint,
it's something that I've always wanted
to do as well. Um, but I also recognize
that it was hard for him. Like it was
something that he gave up. He enjoyed it
too. And uh I know he enjoyed it because
I was right there in his hip watching
him enjoy every minute of it. Um so just
I have a lot of gratitude for him. Um, I
know I'm kind of going off and giving
the the full spiel, but um, just a lot
of gratitude for him and trusting in me,
continuing to invest in me and and uh,
and we both believe this is the right
thing going forward to to propel our
offense forward and for him to focus on
the fold team and and I'm excited to
watch all that unfold.
>> You did get to call the plays once in a
preseason game and I know it's a little
different, but what did you learn from
that experience? Like what were your
major takeaways afterwards? Like, okay,
fix this before time. So, the last
couple years, uh, multiple preseason
games, the 40 second clock is real. It's
that thing goes fast. And once you put a
personnel out, me and Daryl Bevel were
laughing about it today. Once you put
the personnel out there, there's no time
to to pull it back and put a new one
out. Um, so you got to stick to your
guns. Uh, you got to be a play ahead.
Um, that's another thing that, um, I
kind of talk with like the experience
I've had being alongside Dave is he's
always challenged me to I need you to
view the game on game day like a
coordinator. um I need you to be there
for me so we're operating a couple plays
ahead um while everybody else might be
working with substitutions or the
current result. Um I need to have uh
somebody there alongside me. So that fed
into me getting that to flip the roles I
guess if you will um in the preseason
and getting to call it. But he was
always alongside there. It was really
just the same conversations. It's just
who's pressing the button and and giving
the play to the quarterback.
>> How could this help Bryce? Yeah, I think
it's just a constant like I'm there um
I'm there uh in the meeting rooms. Uh
Dave, you know, when you're the head
coach, you get pulled away for uh you
guys. You get pulled away for a bunch of
different things that you have to do as
the head coach. Um but just being um in
tune and in touch with all those small
moments that happen throughout the day.
um I'm there for him and we've had a
great dialogue uh throughout the seasons
as they go and then throughout this off
seasonason how you know really his
evaluation of it all and just continuing
to to invest in that relationship. Um
I'm really looking forward to that. Um
and just looking forward to you know
just just being there for him and
hearing all those things and and getting
it applied as fast as possible to to
what we're trying to accomplish.
>> What was his reaction when you told him
or maybe he'd already been told?
>> Yeah, I think they had probably
previewed it. Um, but I I just talked to
him, I guess an hour ago or so, and he
was excited. Um, I told him how jealous
I was that he was in California right
now and and uh couldn't wait to to link
back up. But we've been touching base
every now and again uh just about
offseason program, getting in touch with
guys and and um for this he's just uh
he's excited for the opportunity just
like it's it's honestly us growing as an
offense, us growing as a team. Um, it's
fun to feel the joy that our guys and
that play between the white lines have
for each other. How our coaches support
each other and and Bryce is uh no
exception to that. He he really uh he
supports my journey just like I support
his.
>> Do you anticipate staying on the field
or do you think you'd want to call from
the box?
>> Uh yeah, I think those are conversations
you get to have like as the the
offseason unfolds. I I love being on the
field for the same thing I was just
mentioning, just feeling out those
little moments of communication that
might not always get through the
headset. Um, so I do love being having
the pulse of the team. Um, what are, you
know, what are guys feeling? You can
only get so much of that from the box.
Um, and then having trusted guys around
me that, you know, the eyes in the sky
with Mike Burkovichi and Keshan Coleman,
uh, this past year, uh, doing a great
job of of show telling us what they're
seeing from up there. Um, but I also
know a lot of a lot of guys do it from
up there and it's a nice, uh, removed
environment to to see the full picture.
So, uh, maybe something that we could,
you know, address and and try out some
different things in in scrimmages and
preseason, uh, play, but I I do say I
prefer to have the pulse of the team on
the sideline.
>> Dave said that when he got his first
play calling job in Tampa Bay, he um,
essentially pitched Todd BS said, "This
is as ready as I'm ever going to be
without having called plays in a real
NFL game." Is that kind of how you feel
that I'm as ready as I can be at this
point?
>> Uh, absolutely. Um, and I think that
goes right right back to uh Dave gets
hired in Tampa. I'm right there. He's
challenging me to think about your next
role as well. I was excited to be a
first-time position coach uh when when I
moved to Tampa. And he said, "I need
more out of you. I need you to think
like I do um so I can have a good
sounding board." Um and over the last
three years, we've continued to build
this offense. and we've had joint
experiences um through his journey as a
play caller um that I think have I'm
able to go ahead and put that in in you
know my briefcase and bring it to work
every day and now you just get to uh
apply all those lessons learned. So
yeah, I do think I'm I'm ready to go. I
I know I'm ready to go. Um I've done it
and uh I'm really excited to apply.
>> Dad, man, and your journey.
>> Oh, I mean it goes without saying. I saw
him just earlier today. Um, my dad's a
big piece. I think everyone would say
their family is a big piece in their up
upbringing and what they believe in, but
also just the football. Um, just just
showing me the ropes, introducing me to
the game. My grandfather as well
coached. Um, so just just being around
here. You talk about being ready like I
grew up in it. I I was literally born a
bi-week baby at Duke University when my
dad was a GA. And um I just there's late
nights in high school throwing routes
with my dad after he's done with work.
there's just all that experience kind of
culminates for me and and now I get to
carve my own journey and I get to share
that with him. Uh that's really special
to me to have him he's he's standing
right over there. So to have him there
um and big moments, you know, where I
get opportunities like this uh when I
get to go back to Tampa and and go to my
hometown and coach in front of him and
he gets to watch me get my first
coordinator job. Um that's really
special to me.
>> So you held on to this he didn't know
prior to finding out today. Uh, I
hinted, yeah, I hinted at it this
morning. I said, "Hey, just make
yourself available this afternoon." Um,
but I'm trying to be as respectful and
tight lipped as possible.
>> Just as a followup, I mean,
understanding that you and Dave, you've
been the offensive coordinator, but now
this is officially going to be your
offense. Um, do you tinker with the
playbook at all or do you leave it as it
is?
>> Uh, we we have a great system of
terminology that we've really sifted
through the last couple years, uh, me
and Dave and and really our whole staff.
I got the guys, a couple guys back home
right now shooting me texts all day
about our general section, some of the
verbiage, things that we can tighten up.
Um, so we have a great support staff of
things that we've problem shot a lot of
things and I I feel like we're in a
really good spot there. Um, as far as
the offense itself, it grows every year.
So, um, every single year we're trying
to apply the offense to who Bryce is, to
our O line, to our skilled players. Um,
and this is a big piece of it being here
at the combine is is finding out, okay,
what are then the other pieces that
we're able to add to the puzzle in the
draft and hopefully Dan's able to get us
some offensive players. I'm going to
fight E for all those offensive slots.
Um, so we can go ahead and expand our
playbook a little bit more, but I think
every year looks a little bit different.
The terminology and all that will be the
same. Um, because we have a great
foundation to work from and our our
quarterback is confident in that. Um,
but the the offense itself will grow as
the team grows. Dave talked about how
holistically this will help him sort of
look at the team as a whole.
>> How tough was it on him to have to call
plays, have to deal with the referee,
have to sort of deal with everything
that comes with being a head coach as
well?
>> Yeah, it's it's a lot. And I just
witnessed secondhand. Um he's got to
have the challenge flag, one hand on the
challenge flag, one hand on the on the
uh the microphone for Bryce, and then
another hand on the call sheet, and then
he's got to get the the pertinent
information from his coaches on both
sides of the ball. Um that's where the
last couple years I've tried to be a
good um sifter for him of information of
just giving him what he needs from the
offensive side. Um so he can have a
clear mind and and operate with speed
and again that 40 second clock is quick.
So giving him the the at the right time
the right pieces of information that
helps him get the play call in. Um it's
a lot though and and I have a lot of uh
respect for the guys that do it as in
the head chair. Um there's a number of
them in the league and and I know that
there's some sacrifice. Maybe it's
sleep, maybe it's time with kids, maybe
whatever it is um that they make to be
able to do that. Um but Dave's done it
gracefully and and I was proud to be,
you know, alongside of him to try to do
what I could to just help him on the
offensive side, keep the information
tight.
>> There's there's 32 play callers in the
NFL in the world, right? I mean, you're
being very professional right now. Has
it like is it exciting? Has it hit you?
Like are you
>> I'm excited. I'm excited. I'm glad to be
excited about this. This is um for me
like again you get into coaching and I
think everyone's like oh I want to be a
head coach. It's a little one foot in
front of the other like my next step was
to get a chance to call plays and um
building something and letting it
watching it unfold and being a part of
how it unfolds um is just the next step
for me and I'm personally just really
excited to to be a part even more a part
of that process of just watching it
unfold on game day. um getting my hands
dirty with it, getting as close as you
can to being a player without being one.
Um and uh and I'm excited to do it with
this the staff we have uh goes without
saying the support staff that we have uh
in Carolina, the guys, some of them are
back home, some of them are here. Um and
the players, the humility they all
operate with, it truly is like it's not
it's not just a personal accomplishment
for me, but it's just another step
forward on on how we're going to operate
uh going forward and making this thing
even better. But honestly, didn't you
think didn't you think honestly that you
were gonna have to go somewhere else to
play calls knowing how much Dave loved
it? Didn't you think one day you'd have
to go somewhere else?
>> Yeah, there's there's a big piece of
loyalty with me and Dave. Um he's
invested in me when others didn't
believe in me. I think I've said that
probably when I first got the job here.
Um that's a guy who when I was a he
helped bring me in as a QC. He stood on
the table for me uh for Brian
Shottenheimer when I I got my first NFL
interview. um he's been there for me
personal uh circumstances and he brought
he brought one guy with him to Tampa and
that was me. He he brought you know
immediately brought me with him to
Carolina as a guy he had to have. So
that's a that's a heavy piece of loyalty
that I have for Dave. It was going to
take a lot to have me ever consider
anything else. Um but I'm just so proud
of what we've built so far, the
trajectory we're on, and I want to be a
part of of seeing that through. Was
there a particular moment that you that
you had where you knew you were ready to
take on?
>> Um, I wouldn't say a particular moment
like I think it was Buffalo the first
year. I got the call I believe the
second half of that Buffalo game and uh
Jaylen Coker was out there, you know,
with some of the younger guys. So that's
that's makes it a little bit easier.
Started throwing some go balls and I'm
like, "Okay, this is fun." I wouldn't
say that meant I was ready. Um, but just
getting the experience and having
somebody, just talking about Dave, who
believes in me, um, push that experience
on me, maybe even before I was ready
when I was in Tampa, giving me a chance
to, hey, this is what it's like. These
are the things I'm going through. Let me
get in his head um, as he's going
through these things. Um, so I can go
ahead and and put that in my pocket and
carry it with me. So I don't I don't put
one moment on it. It's really these last
three years when I've transitioned from
being uh, support staff, you know, QC.
Yes, sir. What can I do? How can I help?
To, hey, I need you to think bigger
picture. Um, so that's really been the
last three years.
>> Brad, what's the play call, excuse me,
the the game planning uh process going
to look like involving you, I'm assuming
Beville at some level and and maybe Dave
still having a hand in it.
>> Yeah, it it'll be very similar. Um, I
think all of our coaches would would
acknowledge that this is a our process
is not a closed door operation where
it's projected onto our staff. I ask all
of our staff to to uh get their hands
dirty in it. They all have areas in
which they are like they are the focal
person for um which information gets
sifted through. So, I see it being very
similar and then adding Daryl Beville to
the mix. um just really the last couple
weeks having get to know him, get to
ping ideas off of him and having his
experience in the room is going to be so
so useful for everyone. And that's what
I told him. I was like I don't want him
to hesitate on imparting his knowledge
and his experience for all of our guys,
not just me. Um we're all going to get
better with having that guy in the room
and uh and if Dave trusts him, I'm
finding out very quickly why who the
human is, um then he's going to fit
right in with our guys.
>> How have you been preparing for this
since being notified? Have you done like
similar?
>> A lot of Madden. A lot of Madden. No,
[laughter] I'm just kidding. Um, no.
It's it's really like honestly it's it's
just prayer and and just being thankful
that um God's afforded me with these
opportunities and to surround me with
these good people. And that's that's the
truth. Um I have a loving wife at home,
Emily, and um I have great friends like
get bombarded with texts before I even
know it's announced. Um, and that guy
right over there, my father, my mother,
like they um, you know, they just make
it like, hey, you deserve this. And, um,
they make it real. You know, when you
you talk to the people that you really
care about and they they're happy for
you in a genuine way, uh, that just that
makes it real for you. [snorts]
[music]